<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/about-us/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-10T19:52:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/about-us/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">UMass Amherst Makerspace | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>UMass Amherst Makerspace Blog</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Meet our staff!</title>
      <link href="/blog/staff-board" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet our staff!" />
      <published>2020-04-08T05:05:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-08T05:05:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/staff-board</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/staff-board">&lt;p&gt;Meet our staff! Here you can find a picture and a quick description of everyone in the makerspace staff, along with an email for each if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kay Bros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/kay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kbros@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Fabric, yarn, thread, LEDs, soft circuits, Arduino/Pi/Lilypad, accessibility, documentation, telescopes/optics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Julius Rosenthal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/julius.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;juliusrosent@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: All things automotive, general repairs &amp; maintenance, hand/power/shop tools, machining, soldering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Philip Van&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/phil.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pvan@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: 3D design &amp; printing, programming, woodworking, mechanical tools, machining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tyler Kerwin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/tyler.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tkerwin@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, construction, drones, mapping, econ/trading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jeremy Paradie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jeremy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jparadie@umass.edu https://www.jeremyparadie.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Batteries, motors, microcontrollers, enclosures, wiring, piezos, servos, power supplies, general electronics, high voltage, tools and machines, design, rapid prototyping, surface mount soldering, reverse engineering, Processing, Arduino, mBed, 3d printing, robotics, Solidworks, Onshape, Altium, Tinkercad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Connor Loughman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/connor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cloughman@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Soldering, math, coding, computer hardware/troubleshooting, woodworking, laser cutting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jack Champagne&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jack.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jrchampagne@umass.edu  www.jackchampage.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Programming (C++, Java, Python), CNC machining, electrical schematics, circuit design, component identification &amp; description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Thomas O’Connor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/thomas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thooconnor@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Environmental studies, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Navya Ravavarapu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/navya.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nravavarapu@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Graphic design, marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Paolo Brandon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/paolo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pbrandon@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Machining, blacksmithing, woodworking, CAD, 3D printing, Illustrator, Photoshop, prototyping, LEGOs, poetry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jessica Scott&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jess.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jessicascott@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Puppet building, puppet mechs, adhesives, basic woodworking, basic casting &amp; molding, basic sewing, soft-sculpture, mask-making, flat-patterning with foam, sculpting, jello and sugar glass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;David Schottler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/david.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dschottler@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Recreational costume design, popsicle sticks, foam crafting, Pepakura&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Margaret Polsgrove&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/margaret.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mpolsgrove@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, basketry, leatherworking, welding, bike repair, Python, Excel, Matlab, Final Cut Pro, circuit debugging, servos/motors, soldering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Costanza Fusco&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/costanza.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;costanzafusc@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, sewing and fiber art, leatherworking, resin casting and mold making, soldering, pattern drafting, painting, basic 3D modeling, LEDs and piezoelectronics, microscopy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Laurel Parsons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/laurel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;laparsons@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Programming, Android Studio, Arduino, basic circuitry, sewing, foamwork, soldering&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Laurel Parsons</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="About Us" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Meet our staff! Here you can find a picture and a quick description of everyone in the makerspace staff, along with an email for each if you have any questions. Kay Bros (she/her/hers) kbros@umass.edu Ask me about: Fabric, yarn, thread, LEDs, soft circuits, Arduino/Pi/Lilypad, accessibility, documentation, telescopes/optics Julius Rosenthal (he/him/his) juliusrosent@umass.edu Ask me about: All things automotive, general repairs &amp; maintenance, hand/power/shop tools, machining, soldering Philip Van (he/him/his) pvan@umass.edu Ask me about: 3D design &amp; printing, programming, woodworking, mechanical tools, machining Tyler Kerwin (he/him/his) tkerwin@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, construction, drones, mapping, econ/trading Jeremy Paradie (he/him/his) jparadie@umass.edu https://www.jeremyparadie.com/ Ask me about: Batteries, motors, microcontrollers, enclosures, wiring, piezos, servos, power supplies, general electronics, high voltage, tools and machines, design, rapid prototyping, surface mount soldering, reverse engineering, Processing, Arduino, mBed, 3d printing, robotics, Solidworks, Onshape, Altium, Tinkercad Connor Loughman (he/him/his) cloughman@umass.edu Ask me about: Soldering, math, coding, computer hardware/troubleshooting, woodworking, laser cutting Jack Champagne (he/him/his) jrchampagne@umass.edu www.jackchampage.com Ask me about: Programming (C++, Java, Python), CNC machining, electrical schematics, circuit design, component identification &amp; description Thomas O’Connor (he/him/his) thooconnor@umass.edu Ask me about: Environmental studies, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), marketing Navya Ravavarapu (she/her/hers) nravavarapu@umass.edu Ask me about: Graphic design, marketing Paolo Brandon (he/him/his) pbrandon@umass.edu Ask me about: Machining, blacksmithing, woodworking, CAD, 3D printing, Illustrator, Photoshop, prototyping, LEGOs, poetry Jessica Scott (she/her/hers) jessicascott@umass.edu Ask me about: Puppet building, puppet mechs, adhesives, basic woodworking, basic casting &amp; molding, basic sewing, soft-sculpture, mask-making, flat-patterning with foam, sculpting, jello and sugar glass David Schottler (he/him/his) dschottler@umass.edu Ask me about: Recreational costume design, popsicle sticks, foam crafting, Pepakura Margaret Polsgrove (she/her/hers) mpolsgrove@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, basketry, leatherworking, welding, bike repair, Python, Excel, Matlab, Final Cut Pro, circuit debugging, servos/motors, soldering Costanza Fusco (she/her/hers) costanzafusc@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, sewing and fiber art, leatherworking, resin casting and mold making, soldering, pattern drafting, painting, basic 3D modeling, LEDs and piezoelectronics, microscopy Laurel Parsons (she/her/hers) laparsons@umass.edu Ask me about: Programming, Android Studio, Arduino, basic circuitry, sewing, foamwork, soldering</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Introduction</title>
      <link href="/blog/staff-intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" />
      <published>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/staff-intro</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/staff-intro">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilities and equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people and expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workshops, and events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as a starting point for most makers on campus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;umamakerspace@umass.edu&quot;&gt;umamakerspace@umass.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Navya Ravavarapu</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="About Us" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines. We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge. A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream. The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus. To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including: facilities and equipment people and expertise workshops, and events To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will: serve as a starting point for most makers on campus provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above. If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to umamakerspace@umass.edu</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
