<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-18T21:48:47+00:00</updated><id>/blog/</id><title type="html">UMass Amherst Makerspace</title><subtitle>UMass Amherst Makerspace Blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="/blog/2020-04-18-Nanoleaf-intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2020-04-18T21:48:47+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T21:48:47+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2020-04-18-Nanoleaf-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020-04-18-Nanoleaf-intro">&lt;p&gt;##Blog 1: Nanoleaf Aurora&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there, my name is Phillip Van and I work for the Umass All-Campus Makerspace. 
Although I have no experience with coding or building circuits, I’ve always wanted to try to make my own Nanoleaf Aurora. 
As a result, this blog will document all of my essential research and findings for you to follow along with and hopefully this will help some of you guys create your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/nanoleaf/nano-wall.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Background: What is the Nanoleaf Aurora&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nanoleaf Aurora is essentially a system of triangular light fixtures with rainbow LEDs (RGB LEDs) inside of them. 
Each triangle is an individual leaf that can connect with other “leaves”. 
As a result, the Nanoleaf is an extremely modular and flexible light fixture that provides a lot of freedom for cool designs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/nanoleaf/musicnote.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s the catch&lt;/strong&gt;, for a set of just nine triangles, the total cost is &lt;strong&gt;$200&lt;/strong&gt;. 
On the other hand, a single 16.4 ft RGB LED strip costs less than $30 and would likely cover more room. 
I figured with the help of google, the Nanoleaf could easily be recreated for a fraction of the cost, below are my initial findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Research:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Googled: Nanoleaf DIY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2OP-oEbzB6g&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2OP-oEbzB6g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:3354082&quot;&gt;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:3354082&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eevblog.com/forum/projects/nanoleaf-aurora-teardown/&quot;&gt;https://www.eevblog.com/forum/projects/nanoleaf-aurora-teardown/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Findings:&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people have done the same projects, creating their own Nanoleaf setup. It seems to be a fairly simple product, consisting of some triangle housings, some LEDS, and a small microcontroller (mini computer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a proof of concept that this project will be more economical than just buying the Nanoleaf here is a general bill of materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/nanoleaf/price.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a $50 price tag, our DIY Nanoleaf will cost approximately a quarter of the original price. In addition, many of these are one time purchases, creating more “leaves” will only make this project more economical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Sneak peak!
Come back in the next blog post, where I play with RGB LEDs to learn how they work!
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/nanoleaf/led.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Algae Cultivation</title><link href="/blog/algae" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Algae Cultivation" /><published>2020-04-18T15:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-18T15:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/algae</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/algae">&lt;p&gt;What’s an algae culture? What’s a new fun use for bog water? Is it really possible to keep a barely sentient plant as a pet? Check out this tutorial on algae cultivation and get answers to all of these questions and more!
(https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10waelMYoLiyHnoneZMJyJejJDivtdQHvx_zKhErg-9s/edit?ts=5e95644a#slide=id.p)[https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10waelMYoLiyHnoneZMJyJejJDivtdQHvx_zKhErg-9s/edit?ts=5e95644a#slide=id.p]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Costanza Fusco</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">What’s an algae culture? What’s a new fun use for bog water? Is it really possible to keep a barely sentient plant as a pet? Check out this tutorial on algae cultivation and get answers to all of these questions and more! (https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10waelMYoLiyHnoneZMJyJejJDivtdQHvx_zKhErg-9s/edit?ts=5e95644a#slide=id.p)[https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/10waelMYoLiyHnoneZMJyJejJDivtdQHvx_zKhErg-9s/edit?ts=5e95644a#slide=id.p]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Surprisingly Simple Process of 3D Modeling with Photogrammetry</title><link href="/blog/Photogrammetry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Surprisingly Simple Process of 3D Modeling with Photogrammetry" /><published>2020-04-11T05:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T05:05:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Photogrammetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Photogrammetry">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-surprisingly-simple-process-of-3d-modeling-with-photogrammetry&quot;&gt;The Surprisingly Simple Process of 3D Modeling with Photogrammetry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen something or someone and thought, “Hey… I’d like to turn this into a 3D model that I can print”. Well think no more, I’m going to tell you how to get started, all you need is a smartphone and a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got started using a drone, where images from above can provide quick and highly accurate models of large areas and buildings. But, the concepts are scalable, and a phone camera works just fine for small objects and people. 
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/agisoft-screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1: Click on &amp;quot;Try it now&amp;quot; to start the free trial and download the product.&quot; /&gt;
Anyway, I used Agisoft Metashape to get started. It is a great product with a 30-day free trial and a very quick, easy download which is compatible
with Linux, Mac, and Windows. Give it a Google
search and find the free trial install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;choose-your-subject&quot;&gt;Choose your Subject&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have Metashape installed, it is time to choose your object or person. I have found that people work best for 3D modeling using smartphones because of the texture, size, opacity, and reflectivity of human faces, but the right object can work just as well given the right circumstances. Professional photogrammeters use rigs in order to perfectly capture every angle of an object with a consistently lit surface.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/camera-setup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2: This is a very professional setup as an example of stationary cameras and stationary subjects.&quot; /&gt;
For the purposes of this post, however, we leave the object or person stationary on the floor (or standing) and rotate the camera around it/them at many different (eyeballed) angles.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/at-home.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3: In this setup, a small object remains stationary while the camera rotates around it at set angles, with the same background.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-good-subject-means-that-it-is&quot;&gt;A good subject means that it is:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/face.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
-A person: people work really well in amateur photogrammetry processes because of likely bad lighting and the effectiveness of handheld smartphone cameras. This screenshot is my second attempt at a person. I only used about 65 images, and got subpar results, which is much better than it could have gone using so few images and terrible lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/weird-fuckin-thing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
-A larger object with low reflectivity and high opacity. Smaller objects don’t work as well with poor lighting and background because Metashape can’t tell what is the floor or what is the object – in other words, the depth is bad. Photogrammetric software has a lot of trouble understanding why reflective and see-through objects look so different from different angles. This table was the first object I attempted to model, it has a transparent glass top. It came out terrible – like a muffin too big for its container. This is because Metashape couldn’t understand what images belonged where in the model due to the see-through top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-the-photos&quot;&gt;Take the Photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your subject, find a wide open area with pretty consistent lightning. So, close windows, turn on overhead lights, and clear an area with about a 3foot radius around your subject, you will need more room than you think. If it’s cloudy outside, then that is perfect.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/garage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 4: Garages are great!&quot; /&gt;
Next take out your smartphone and photograph the subject! For the purpose of this, just have the subject stay stationary and rotate around with your camera. Auto settings are fine. The idea is to photograph 360 degrees around your subject at many different angles. So directly above (90 degrees), then slightly lower at about 65 degrees, then 35 degrees, then 0 degrees. This doesn’t have to be exact; the models will likely look like a first try. Try to get a decent amount of overlap as you rotate around the subject, but about 50 photos is plenty for your first model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;upload-and-process-in-metashape&quot;&gt;Upload and Process in Metashape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard part is over! Next, import your photos to Metashape as indicated in the figure below.
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/metashape.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
The rest of the process is very simple, but it does take time. Basically it will all be done in the workflow tab: 
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/selection.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select them, and apply the processes in descending order. So, align the photos, then build dense cloud, then mesh, then texture. Each process will make the model look more and more like the real thing. Note: you must continuously crop during each step. You can do this very easily by using the crop tool: 
After you select points and areas which will be of the room you are modeling in, click the X two spaces the the right of the crop tool. This will delete the selected points. Alternatively, select the parts you want to keep and click the “crop selected” button three to the right of the crop tool in order to delete everything other than the selected. If you crop nothing, you will get something like this: 
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/photogram-finished.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
After each step, you can view progress by selecting “point cloud”, “dense cloud”, and “texture/mesh” views: 
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/textures.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another note: To hide the weird blue squares (which actually indicate where the picture was take and what angle relative to the subject), grid, and trackball, simply click Model 🡪 Show/hide items and then click whatever you don’t want to see anymore. 
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/fix.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Default settings will be fine for this, with medium accuracy all around the board for quicker processing times. If you want a really crisp model, then increase the accuracy levels and it is very important to increase tie point limit and key tie point limit under advanced settings during the align photos phase (around 80,000+ and 10,000+ respectively).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are still with me, you should be able to make a pretty good 3D model! If you try, and the photos don’t align (I usually look for about 80% of photos to align) or the model comes out terrible, it unfortunately is likely due to poor photos. There is no solution around that other than retake the photos in a different space with potentially a different object. But, that is the best way to learn what works and what doesn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you so desire, these files can be exported and done with as you please. In the coming weeks, a new blog post and workshop will be posted on how to 3D print these files. So we can essentially 3D print a human. The week after that will be giving it artificial intelligence, then you can have your very own UMass makerspace clone!
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/photogram/spiderman-pointing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tyler Kerwin</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">The Surprisingly Simple Process of 3D Modeling with Photogrammetry</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Worst Car Ever Made</title><link href="/blog/Trabant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Worst Car Ever Made" /><published>2020-04-10T01:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T01:11:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Trabant</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Trabant">&lt;p&gt;Hello! Welcome to the Makerspace Automotive Newsletter! I’m Julius and I’m here to bring you an occasional blog post to teach you about automotive history, talk about current interesting innovations and happenings in the world of cars, and generally provide my commentary on all things automotive. Be it electric, gas, sedan, pickup, commuter or race, it’s like the wild freaking west out here and nothing is off limits….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, to kick things off I figured we could start with a little snippet of automotive history. A particular vehicle near and dear to my heart. The worst car ever made: &lt;strong&gt;The Trabant&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Trabant&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Trabant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictured above is a Trabant P50. I think it’s a 1959 model but honestly, don’t quote me on that because every year of this thing basically looks the same. At first glance you might be thinking: “Damn, Julius, that thing is kind of ugly, I guess, but mostly just a boring Euro-ish car. Why should I give a damn?” Well foolish reader, I’m here to tell you about how the Trabant was not only the WORST smelling car in automotive history, but how it’s a symbol of liberation, the fall of East Berlin, and the fight against communism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold up. We need some background info first. Time for a quick German history lesson. In case you’re not totally familiar with your German history, here’s the gist of it. After WWII everyone hated everyone else, especially if they were a communist. Berlin was split down the middle where the West was governed by the Allies and the East was controlled by the Soviet Union. A wall was built 1961 that divided the two sides. That’s the Berlin Wall. Maybe you heard of it, maybe not, doesn’t matter.  The West refused to recognize the communist East and tensions were DUMMY high. Also, life big time sucked in East Berlin. Now you know all you need to know about East and West Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for our little Trabant friend? Well, the Trabant was manufactured in East Berlin. Actually, it was basically the ONLY car manufactured in East Berlin. As such, it provides a concise answer to the question that nobody was really asking: “What does a car look like when a nation has no means to build a car?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Newly born Trabant 601s. Released in 1967, these were essentially the final form of the Trabant as it remained virtually unchanged until production stopped. That said, these were barely even an upgrade from the original models.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Newly born Trabant 601s. Released in 1967, these were essentially the final form of the Trabant as it remained virtually unchanged until production stopped. That said, these were barely even an upgrade from the original models.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s dive in. The Trabant was manufactured from 1957 to 1990 by VEB Sachsenring. During its production, 3.7 million of these things were built. It was a front-engine, front wheel drive 2-door sedan (with a 3-door station wagon option available in certain years). Due to a severe metal shortage, its body was constructed out of a hard type of plastic called Duroplast, which was made of resin, reinforced with recycled fabrics like wool and cotton. Yep, so back in the day you would quite literally be driving around in some stranger’s discarded underwear. Or that ugly knit sweater you got as a gift from your aunt and then “misplaced.” Now that sweater is someone’s grocery-getter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Trabant was the first production car to ever be constructed out of recycled materials.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Trabant was the first production car to ever be constructed out of recycled materials.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image5.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Trabant’s Engine weighed only 40kg. And if you take away all the body panels, this is all you get. This is everything that makes the Trabi go. Truly wack.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Trabant’s Engine weighed only 40kg. And if you take away all the body panels, this is all you get. This is everything that makes the Trabi go. Truly wack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sweater was powered by a 500cc (.5L/31cu.in.) two cylinder, two stroke, air-cooled engine (later models were upgraded to a whopping 600cc). While sometimes used in certain older automotive applications, a two stroke engine is more commonly found in applications such as dirt bikes, power tools, lawnmowers, that kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was truly the Little Engine That Couldn’t, but it had one very impressive aspect which was the fact that it was built with only 5 moving parts, drastically reducing wear and materials. 5 moving parts in an engine is NUTS. A typical V8 engine has something like 200+ moving parts not even considering the various accessories required to cool and power the thing. Everything about this car was so incredibly simple that any mom, dad, child, dog, cat, or vegetable could service this thing. All things said, the Trabant made 18 horsepower (25 by the end of its production). If you need me to put that into perspective, your mom’s new-ish toyota corolla makes about 130 horsepower and doesn’t suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every engine needs lubrication (change your oil, folks). Usually this is achieved by having a complete system which circulates oil throughout the engine, pumping it wherever it needs to be. The Trabant didn’t have any of that (Why add extra moving parts when you could just use one intake for both the oil AND the gas?). You refueled the trabant by mixing up gasoline and oil in the 6 gallon tank (~50:1 ratio) and shaking it up a bunch to mix it all up. The effect of this? This bastard smoked more than a cuban prime minister and THAT is the key component of why the Trabant smelled so bad: it was literally just burning oil by design. And if it’s not obvious, perpetually burning oil in such volume smells TERRIBLE. Not to mention you were basically taking a gatling gun to the ozone layer. This smoke machine produced nine times the hydrocarbons and five times the carbon-monoxide emissions than the average Euro car in 2007 (that’s… A LOT). Definitely not an emissions-compliant vehicle here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Although the factory guidelines stated a 50:1 Fuel to Oil ratio. Many Berliners were known to increase the quantity of oil, falsely believing it would increase engine reliability and longevity. More oil = more smoke = more stank.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Although the factory guidelines stated a 50:1 Fuel to Oil ratio. Many Berliners were known to increase the quantity of oil, falsely believing it would increase engine reliability and longevity. More oil = more smoke = more stank.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what was it really like to drive around in one of these things? What kind of creature comforts and convenience items could you expect (other than a built in James Bond-style smoke screen everywhere you went)? Cooled seats? Heated steering wheel? Adaptive climate control? No, of course not, dummy. The trabant was a (literal) pain in the ass to own, and in keeping with the general theme of East Berlin at the time, the driver’s seat of the Trabant was a deadly place to inhabit. Let’s just go over a FEW of the weird aspects of this car that any Trabi owner would have to cope with on a day to day basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that bit about refueling with a witch’s brew of oil and gas? Well this thing had no gas gauge, so to figure out how much gas was left, you would have to go outside, pop the hood, and check the level of the fuel tank with a little dipstick. And yes, you read that right. The fuel tank was located ABOVE the engine in a FRONT ENGINE vehicle. This effectively eliminated the need for a fuel pump as gravity would pull fuel out of the tank and straight into the engine. It also effectively eliminated the need for seat belts because a relatively minor collision could result in a fiery explosion that would probably just kill you anyways. Later models did get front seat belts, but rear passengers were always considered expendable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what features did this car have? Gas gauge? Nope. Seat belts? Lmao. Living to see your daughter’s wedding? Not in one of these you don’t. Reverse &amp;amp; hazard lights? An option if you had the extra cash! How about door locks? This is actually a feature the Trabant came equipped with. But it worked like this: the driver’s door could be locked/unlocked from the outside but not the inside, and the passenger’s door could be locked/unlocked from the inside but not the outside. Why, you ask? I don’t know, Communism or something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything that could be manually operated on this car was… operated manually… Even down to the windshield washer fluid. Normally when you get dust and dirt on your windshield you push a button and a little electric motor sprays fluid over the glass. But that sounds like a lot of extra, useless nonsense compared to Trabant’s method: a plunger that you push and pull on the dashboard that manually pumps the fluid onto the windshield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Typical Trabant interior, except this one is lucky enough to have a radio.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Typical Trabant interior, except this one is lucky enough to have a radio.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to imagine this. It’s 1981 and you’re a reluctant resident of East Berlin. You need to go get some groceries so you grab your keys and head outside to your lovely Trabant 601. You pop the hood and take out the little dipstick, dipping it into the engine and, alas, there is not enough fuel. You grab a pre-mixed container of gas and oil and give it a few shakes to make sure it’s all mixed up to top off your tank. Hopping onto the hard, non-conforming seats, you give the windshield a few pumps of cleaner which does absolutely nothing. You make peace with the lord as you start the car because prayer is your most promising safety feature. It stalls on the first few attempts, as you need to keep your foot on the gas for it to stay running (you can only cruise in 4th gear… sometimes…). Eventually you get to driving down the road, eyes burning from the exhaust smoke as you make your way downtown, imagery of being engulfed in the flames of your front-mounted gas tank filling your mind. You arrive, somehow unscathed, but you’ve forgotten your own name because of the carbon monoxide poisoning. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Trabi truly was that awful. It was a terrible vehicle from every perspective except for cost management. Owning this car was a painful, shitty experience, but then again so was every aspect of life in East Berlin, and they didn’t exactly have many (any) options to choose from. Nonetheless, the Trabi would go on to solidify its place in history, becoming a badass little symbol of triumph against Communism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered all the aspects of the Trabant that make it awful, let’s talk about the things that make it, well, kind of badass actually. The public image of the Trabant is mixed. For many former East Berliners, it painfully (and accurately) represented the absurd conditions that had to be endured under Communist rule: slow, unreliable, and dangerous. Many Trabants were left to rot in abandonment out of pain and spite. However, to others, the Trabant stands as a symbol of triumph, after surviving the difficult times of the era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those days, the Trabant was sometimes modified to be used as an agent to smuggle people from East Berlin into the West across the wall. When rare occasions presented that folks were allowed to cross, citizens were sometimes smuggled in the trunks, and sometimes even in the engine compartments of the Trabant, some being modified to allow more occupancy and discretion. The clown-car shenanigans that were pulled in these vehicles put any circus to shame, and these were performed in the name of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As times progressed on the Western side of the Iron Curtain, the automotive industry leapt into the 70s and 80s, with computer-controlled engines, electronic fuel injection, and emissions control, but the trabant remained virtually unchanged. A stark representation of the decline of Soviet power. By the late 80s, border control between East and West weakened and the lines of Trabants snaked their way out of East Berlin in what is now known as the “Trabi Trail,” seeking out new lives beyond the wall. In 1989 the Berlin Wall officially fell, and citizens flooded the streets in their Trabants, followed by the blue exhaust fumes, dubbed “the perfume of freedom.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image9.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Trabi Trail&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Trabi Trail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the Trabant has become something of a collectors item, and a tourist attraction. Many seek out these cars, some being modified in fun creative ways and others being restored and kept as tokens of German history. You can see these cars all over Germany still, being led in tourist convoys (pay some ridiculous amount of money and drive a trabant) or in car meets. You can always tell when one is nearby the horrible buzzing sound it makes and the smell from a mile away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the wall came down, the Trabi became a popular subject in media and culture, and the subject of numerous movies (typically as a method of indirectly making fun of the Soviet government). Ever see that freaky show, Herbie? The one about the sentient VW Beetle that… races? Or something? Well anyways, there’s a Trabi knockoff of that show. There even grew to be some superstitions surrounding the car, with some believing that Green Trabants bring good luck (which hilariously drives up their market price).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trabi is a freaky little deathtrap. It’s fun and easy to laugh at it and make into an easy target for an automotive writing piece. Nonetheless, you can’t kick these tires without acknowledging the legitimate historical significance of this car. The Trabant’s existence is a reminder of not only the liberation of the Eastern Bloc, but of all the turmoil that led up to it under Soviet powers. If you would like to learn more about terrible cars throughout history, current happenings in the industry, or any other topics of automotive interest, make sure to follow up on The Umass Makerspace Blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image10.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Trabant, immortalized in art.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Trabant, immortalized in art.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/trabant/image11.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trabi World&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julius Rosenthal</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">Hello! Welcome to the Makerspace Automotive Newsletter! I’m Julius and I’m here to bring you an occasional blog post to teach you about automotive history, talk about current interesting innovations and happenings in the world of cars, and generally provide my commentary on all things automotive. Be it electric, gas, sedan, pickup, commuter or race, it’s like the wild freaking west out here and nothing is off limits….</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet our staff!</title><link href="/blog/staff-board" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet our staff!" /><published>2020-04-08T05:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-08T05:05:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/staff-board</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/staff-board">&lt;p&gt;Meet our staff! Here you can find a picture and a quick description of everyone in the makerspace staff, along with an email for each if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kay Bros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/kay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kbros@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Fabric, yarn, thread, LEDs, soft circuits, Arduino/Pi/Lilypad, accessibility, documentation, telescopes/optics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Julius Rosenthal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/julius.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;juliusrosent@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: All things automotive, general repairs &amp; maintenance, hand/power/shop tools, machining, soldering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Philip Van&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/phil.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pvan@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: 3D design &amp; printing, programming, woodworking, mechanical tools, machining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tyler Kerwin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/tyler.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tkerwin@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, construction, drones, mapping, econ/trading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jeremy Paradie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jeremy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jparadie@umass.edu https://www.jeremyparadie.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Batteries, motors, microcontrollers, enclosures, wiring, piezos, servos, power supplies, general electronics, high voltage, tools and machines, design, rapid prototyping, surface mount soldering, reverse engineering, Processing, Arduino, mBed, 3d printing, robotics, Solidworks, Onshape, Altium, Tinkercad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Connor Loughman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/connor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cloughman@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Soldering, math, coding, computer hardware/troubleshooting, woodworking, laser cutting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jack Champagne&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jack.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jrchampagne@umass.edu  www.jackchampage.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Programming (C++, Java, Python), CNC machining, electrical schematics, circuit design, component identification &amp; description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Thomas O’Connor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/thomas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thooconnor@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Environmental studies, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Navya Ravavarapu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/navya.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nravavarapu@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Graphic design, marketing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Paolo Brandon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/paolo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pbrandon@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Machining, blacksmithing, woodworking, CAD, 3D printing, Illustrator, Photoshop, prototyping, LEGOs, poetry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jessica Scott&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/jess.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jessicascott@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Puppet building, puppet mechs, adhesives, basic woodworking, basic casting &amp; molding, basic sewing, soft-sculpture, mask-making, flat-patterning with foam, sculpting, jello and sugar glass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;David Schottler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/david.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(he/him/his)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dschottler@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Recreational costume design, popsicle sticks, foam crafting, Pepakura&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Margaret Polsgrove&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/margaret.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mpolsgrove@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, basketry, leatherworking, welding, bike repair, Python, Excel, Matlab, Final Cut Pro, circuit debugging, servos/motors, soldering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Costanza Fusco&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/costanza.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;costanzafusc@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Woodworking, sewing and fiber art, leatherworking, resin casting and mold making, soldering, pattern drafting, painting, basic 3D modeling, LEDs and piezoelectronics, microscopy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Laurel Parsons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/UMass-Makerspace/blog2/master/assets/images/profile-pics/laurel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(she/her/hers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;laparsons@umass.edu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask me about: Programming, Android Studio, Arduino, basic circuitry, sewing, foamwork, soldering&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laurel Parsons</name></author><category term="About Us" /><summary type="html">Meet our staff! Here you can find a picture and a quick description of everyone in the makerspace staff, along with an email for each if you have any questions. Kay Bros (she/her/hers) kbros@umass.edu Ask me about: Fabric, yarn, thread, LEDs, soft circuits, Arduino/Pi/Lilypad, accessibility, documentation, telescopes/optics Julius Rosenthal (he/him/his) juliusrosent@umass.edu Ask me about: All things automotive, general repairs &amp; maintenance, hand/power/shop tools, machining, soldering Philip Van (he/him/his) pvan@umass.edu Ask me about: 3D design &amp; printing, programming, woodworking, mechanical tools, machining Tyler Kerwin (he/him/his) tkerwin@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, construction, drones, mapping, econ/trading Jeremy Paradie (he/him/his) jparadie@umass.edu https://www.jeremyparadie.com/ Ask me about: Batteries, motors, microcontrollers, enclosures, wiring, piezos, servos, power supplies, general electronics, high voltage, tools and machines, design, rapid prototyping, surface mount soldering, reverse engineering, Processing, Arduino, mBed, 3d printing, robotics, Solidworks, Onshape, Altium, Tinkercad Connor Loughman (he/him/his) cloughman@umass.edu Ask me about: Soldering, math, coding, computer hardware/troubleshooting, woodworking, laser cutting Jack Champagne (he/him/his) jrchampagne@umass.edu www.jackchampage.com Ask me about: Programming (C++, Java, Python), CNC machining, electrical schematics, circuit design, component identification &amp; description Thomas O’Connor (he/him/his) thooconnor@umass.edu Ask me about: Environmental studies, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), marketing Navya Ravavarapu (she/her/hers) nravavarapu@umass.edu Ask me about: Graphic design, marketing Paolo Brandon (he/him/his) pbrandon@umass.edu Ask me about: Machining, blacksmithing, woodworking, CAD, 3D printing, Illustrator, Photoshop, prototyping, LEGOs, poetry Jessica Scott (she/her/hers) jessicascott@umass.edu Ask me about: Puppet building, puppet mechs, adhesives, basic woodworking, basic casting &amp; molding, basic sewing, soft-sculpture, mask-making, flat-patterning with foam, sculpting, jello and sugar glass David Schottler (he/him/his) dschottler@umass.edu Ask me about: Recreational costume design, popsicle sticks, foam crafting, Pepakura Margaret Polsgrove (she/her/hers) mpolsgrove@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, basketry, leatherworking, welding, bike repair, Python, Excel, Matlab, Final Cut Pro, circuit debugging, servos/motors, soldering Costanza Fusco (she/her/hers) costanzafusc@umass.edu Ask me about: Woodworking, sewing and fiber art, leatherworking, resin casting and mold making, soldering, pattern drafting, painting, basic 3D modeling, LEDs and piezoelectronics, microscopy Laurel Parsons (she/her/hers) laparsons@umass.edu Ask me about: Programming, Android Studio, Arduino, basic circuitry, sewing, foamwork, soldering</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Everything to know about Drills</title><link href="/blog/drills" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything to know about Drills" /><published>2020-04-06T01:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-06T01:11:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/drills</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/drills">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hand-tools-cordless-drill---torque-speed-uses&quot;&gt;Hand Tools: Cordless Drill - Torque, Speed, Uses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most used tools in any shop will likely be a cordless drill. At the UMass Amherst Makerspace, we use Milwaukee M18 Fuel ½” hammer drill/drivers. In many words, it’s this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our drill of choice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drills are easy and generally very safe tools, and can make holes in material (wood, metal, masonry), and they can attach two materials together using screws. This all sounds dumb right? Everybody knows what a drill is and how to use it - you just pull the trigger and walk away. This is true! But, not everybody knows how to use drills the &lt;em&gt;right way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is grab a battery and a drill from our charging station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Drill battery and charger&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Drill battery (left) and charger (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slide the battery into the slot on the drill. Next, you need a bit. Depending on what size hole you will be drilling, or what type of screw you are driving you will need a bit with the corresponding size and shape. To choose a bit for driving screws, find the screw you want and try pushing your bit into the top of it. If it fits snugly, you’ve got the right bit! To decide on a bit to drive a hole, you want to find one that is just slightly bigger than the screw you’ll be using. To install the bit, twist the black piece on the drill that is located right past the torque dial (grey rotating piece). Twisting this loosens and tightens the drill’s grip on bits, or the chuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Philips head drill bit, used for driving screws&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Drill bits used for drilling holes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: How to insert a drill bit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adjusting-speed-and-torque&quot;&gt;Adjusting Speed and Torque&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To adjust the speed, flip the black switch located on top. There will be a 1 (slow) and a 2 (fast) setting. Typically, if you are driving screws you will want higher speeds, and drilling holes you will want lower speeds. This then brings torque into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To adjust torque, simply twist the grey dial with numbers 1-14 and a couple symbols on it. To drill a hole, switch the speed to 1, and adjust the torque to the drill setting (it looks like a drill bit, and is the highest torque possible). Drilling holes is best done with &lt;strong&gt;low speed and high torque.&lt;/strong&gt; Driving screws is a bit different: start with high speed and the lowest torque possible. Each time the drill won’t drive the screw any deeper, move up in torque. Continue this process until the screw is flush with the material you are screwing into. Whatever number you landed on is what you should continue the project on (this is the torque required for whatever material you are using). Adjust as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/drills/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Drill overhead&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well if you made it this far then you are a pro on drilling now. If you skipped to the bottom, then here is a video for you instead: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O8rINDIWU-g&quot;&gt;Drills for Dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tyler Kerwin</name></author><category term="articles" /><summary type="html">Hand Tools: Cordless Drill - Torque, Speed, Uses</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="/blog/tech0" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/tech0</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/tech0">&lt;p&gt;Connor and Jack take you through the history of computing and through a brief understanding of the components that make up modern computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check them  out on Youtube here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;910&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d22ChiaMofg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Jack Champagne</name></author><category term="Tech series" /><summary type="html">Connor and Jack take you through the history of computing and through a brief understanding of the components that make up modern computers. Check them out on Youtube here!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="/blog/staff-intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/staff-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/staff-intro">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilities and equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people and expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workshops, and events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as a starting point for most makers on campus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;umamakerspace@umass.edu&quot;&gt;umamakerspace@umass.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Navya Ravavarapu</name></author><category term="About Us" /><summary type="html">Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines. We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge. A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream. The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus. To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including: facilities and equipment people and expertise workshops, and events To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will: serve as a starting point for most makers on campus provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above. If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to umamakerspace@umass.edu</summary></entry></feed>