<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/author/navya/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-18T20:10:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/author/navya/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">UMass Amherst Makerspace | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>UMass Amherst Makerspace Blog</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Introduction</title>
      <link href="/blog/staff-intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" />
      <published>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-04T06:40:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/staff-intro</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/staff-intro">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilities and equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people and expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workshops, and events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as a starting point for most makers on campus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;umamakerspace@umass.edu&quot;&gt;umamakerspace@umass.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Navya Ravavarapu</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="About Us" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome to the staff of the UMass Amherst Makerspace The UMass Amherst Makerspace is an interdisciplinary makerspace open to students, staff, and faculty from all majors and disciplines. We provide access to space, tools, equipment, training, and help connect individuals and facilitate mentorship and sharing of knowledge. A major focus of the makerspace is re-use, repair, and re-purposing. We want to reduce waste and costs by serving as a hub for the community to share used tools, equipment, materials, furniture, and more. Much of what we have has been donated or saved from the campus waste stream. The UMass Amherst Maker Network is an ongoing project to connect students, faculty, and staff with resources for making all over campus. To connect the UMass Amherst maker community with information and access pathways to existing resources on campus, including: facilities and equipment people and expertise workshops, and events To create a central All-Campus Makerspace, which will: serve as a starting point for most makers on campus provide access to training and equipment for many common maker technologies serve as the campus maker community focal point and host events related to making Our temporary location for Spring 2020 is the Astronomy Building, located near ELab and the Gunness Laboratory at the location indicated on the map above. If you would like to visit the makerspace in this location and are looking to plan your visit with accessibility in mind, send an email to umamakerspace@umass.edu</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
